JEREMIAH ABAH

2120 Ramrod Ave ◆ Henderson, Nevada 89014 (480) 527 - 4686 ◆ jerryleads1@gmail.com <u>GitHub</u>

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced full stack software developer with a diverse background in object-oriented programming and web development. Currently holds a Master of Information Technology (MSIT) with a concentration in Software Application Development from Southern New Hampshire University.

SKILLS

• HTML

ReactJS

• Git/GitHub

• CSS

• Mysql

• Microsoft Azure

• Bootstrap

C#

• Windows and Mac OS

JavaScript

ASP.NET

• REST APIs

jQuery

• Entity Framework

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Developer Internship TrueCoders | Hoover, AL

August 2020 - October 2020

Created multiple projects including:

- A portfolio website site using HTML5, CSS3, BOOTSRAP, JS & jQuery.
- A fully functional Tech Blog Website with implemented enhanced role & security features, used a Code First Relational Database designed in SQL Server (MSSM), deployed on Azure. Technologies used include C#, ASP.NET, LINQ, SQL, Entity Framework, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery Data Tables and Razor Pages.
- Designed an ecommerce website using Database First Approach in SQL, implemented enhanced login & security, an admin page, and checkout features. Technologies used include: ASP.NET, MVC5, C#, LINQ, SQL, Entity Framework, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and Razor Pages.

Information Technology Systems Technician Clark County | Las Vegas, NV

May 2020 - June 2020

- Assisted in providing software and hardware support (design, installs, tests, document, and maintain local area network systems; troubleshoot and resolve hardware and software issues).
- Actively participate in providing 2020 Election IT support/setup of multiple networks of computer systems
 used in various locations.
- Perform various software upgrades or assigned chores under the supervision of the IT Department head.

IT Support/Audio Visual Technician

July 2017 - April 2020

Encore Event Technologies | Las Vegas, NV

- I performed daily set-up and troubleshooting of computers and Audio/Visual equipment for clients.
- Provided IT support to the client whenever services are needed.
- I trained 5 new employees on departmental procedures and excellent performance of daily duties.

IT Specialist, Technical and Media Coordinator Solid Rock Phoenix | Glendale, Arizona

March 2016 - June 2017

- I provided IT support for all organization's offices and trained users on new technologies.
- I performed regular updates on organization's WordPress website, social media and blog pages.
- I provided professional audio-visual services during organization's live events and broadcasts.
- Coordinated Inventory & maintenance of all equipment, and mentored all technical volunteers..

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Information Technology

November 2019

Southern New Hampshire University, Manchester, NH

Bachelor of Arts in Music December 2011

Obafemi Awolowo University, Ife, Osun

Google IT Support Professional Certificate May 2020

REFERENCES

Name: Robert Eisenberg | Position: Director of Event Technologies, Encore Event Technologies, Las Vegas, NV

Relationship: Former Boss | Contact: roberteisenberg@encore-us.com | Phone: (702) 239 - 1269

Name: Paul Maynard | Position: Manager of Event Technologies, Encore Event Technologies, Las Vegas, NV

Relationship: Former Boss | Contact: paulmaynard@encore-us.com | Phone: (702) 343 – 8953

Name: Mark Matthews | Position: Senior Supervisor, IT Systems Technician, Clark County Nevada

Relationship: Former Boss | Contact: MarkM@clarkcountyny.gov | Phone: (702) 717 - 2465